

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · EVENT STREAMING

73 Forest Run Blvd, Concord, ON, L4K5J6, Canada

□ (+1) 647-219-6236 | waismanedward@gmail.com | □ eddyv | □ edwardvaisman

Professional Summary.

Software developer with 4 years of professional experience and a potent interest for event-driven architecture. Proficiency in operating multi-region distributed streaming platforms like apache kafka on aws. Extensive software development life-cycle experience exercised from start to finsh along with prominent communication skills and constructive attitude.

Experience

BMO Financial Group

Toronto, ON

DEVELOPER

Sept. 2018 - PRESENT

- · Helped build real-time streaming data pipelines to reliably get data between systems and applications.
- Designed & implemented a real-time data pipeline that is field level encrypted to allow for data transfer between our kafka cluster on-premises and our kafka cluster in the cloud(AWS).
- Built real-time streaming applications that transform & react to streams of data.
- Automated approaches to streamline and integrate technological processes and/or systems to improve operational efficiency and effectiveness.
- Conceived and wrote detailed software implementations while ensuring that their code adhere to the security, logging, error handling, and performance standards and non-functional requirements.
- Demonstrated detailed application of software knowledge through the production of a series of projects including:
 Application Development (Java, KafkaStreams, KafkaConnect); Other (XSLT/XML, JSON, AVRO, WSDL, HTML, CSS3, Javascript, React, Git, Ansible, Bamboo);

Viacoremedia Toronto, ON

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER May. 2016 - Sept. 2018

- Developed excellent time-management skills through deadline driven projects and tasks.
- · Responsible for management of web pages, email hosting, web hosting.
- Responsible for creating scalable robust web pages; information gathering, planning, developing, testing, debugging code and designing interfaces
- Created multiple scalable, responsive, and robust PPC web pages with high conversion rates.
- · Worked with clients and project managers to determine the scope and goals of their web pages such as SEO Optimization.
- Gathered and analyzed data for website optimization and presentation to the client.
- Demonstrated detailed application of software knowledge through the production of a series of projects including: Animations (CSS3, JQuery); Scripting (PHP, Javascript, JQuery, Google Apps Scripts); CMS(Wordpress).

Skills

Programming Java, C#, C/C++, Turing, XNA Game Studio, Linux, Python.

Web HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap Framework, Express with Node.JS, PHP, MYSQL, WordPress.

Big Data Confluent Kafka, Kafka Connect, Avro.

Cloud AWS S3, AWS Secrets Manager, Serverless Framework.

Monitoring Tools Dynatrace.

DevOps Tools GitLab, GitHub, BitBucket, Ansible, Bamboo, Maven.

Languages English, Russian.

Education

York University

Toronto, Canada

B.Sc., Spec. Hons. Computer Science (Software Development)

Sept. 2013 - April. 2018

 $Recognized \ as \ top \ 15\% \ of \ all \ students \ in \ my \ program, \ apart \ of \ the \ Golden \ Key \ International \ Honour \ Society.$

Extracurricular Activity

Software Development Capstone Project (York University)

Toronto, ON

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & DESIGN

Sept. 2017 - April. 2018

- Developed a new graduate application system for the EECS graduate department aimed to help review/find suitable graduate student candidates.
- Built using Express with Node.JS, MYSQL database and a Mochajs test framework.

York University ACM Programming Contests

Toronto, ON

COMPETITOR

CORE MEMBER

Jun. 2013 - April. 2018

- Competed against fellow classmates to solve as many questions as possible.
- Able to apply several advanced topics such as Dynamic Programming and Greedy Algorithms.

CSGAMES (York University Team)

Montreal, QC 2016 - 2017

• Competed alongside fellow classmates universities nation wide for the CS Cup.

• Participated in the following competitions: Mobile Development, Web Development, Theoretical Computer Science, Algorithms.

JUNE 22, 2020 EDWARD VAISMAN · RÉSUMÉ